realsport101.com 2019-07-17

# Website Privacy Policy - RealSport

This website is operated by Realsm Limited, 173 West End Lane, West Hampstead, London NW6 2LY. Any reference in this policy to “we”, “us” or “our” is to Realsm Limited.

We are part of a group of companies known as Gfinity Group (which includes [Gfinity PLC](https://www.gfinityplc.com/) and [CEVO](http://cevo.com/)). We may share your personal information with other members of our group in accordance with the terms of this privacy policy.

We are the data controller (the company that’s responsible for deciding how your personal data is used) and take your privacy very seriously. Therefore, we urge you to read this privacy policy carefully because it contains important information about us and:

  * The personal data we collect about you, our users;
  * What we do with your information; and
  * Who your information may be shared with.

If you don’t understand any part of this privacy policy, you can always contact us with questions by email using [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) _._

## **What personal data do we collect**

The table below sets out what personal data we collect about you and how we collect it. We may combine any of this personal data together (for example, combining your visits to our website with your activity history) for the purposes explained in this privacy policy.

**Data we collect** | **How we collect it**  
---|---  
Identity data (first name, last name, username or similar identifier, gender, birth date, nationality)  | Provided by you on registration or otherwise through a direct interaction with us  
Contact data (email address)  | Provided by you on registration or otherwise through a direct interaction with us   
Profile data (profile picture, social network account details, game account id’s/details, account preferences)  | Optional information provided on registration or otherwise through a direct interaction with us  
Technical data (IP address, browser type, hardware type, network and software identifiers, system configuration information, location data, device information)

| Using automated technologies or interactions (such as cookies and other similar technologies)  
Usage data (visits to and use of our website, activity history, engagement data including “clicks and opens”) | Using automated technologies or interactions (such as cookies and other similar technologies)   
Marketing and communications data (marketing preferences in respect of us and third parties)  | Provided by you on registration or otherwise through a direct interaction with us  
  
We also collect, use and share aggregated data such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated data is not considered personal data in law as it does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. However, if we combine aggregated data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we will treat the combined data as personal data and use it in accordance with this privacy policy.

## **How will your personal data be used?**

The table below sets out how we use your personal data and what our lawful basis for processing your personal data is. We may process your personal data for more than one lawful basis depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your personal data. We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to.

Generally, we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than in relation to sending direct marketing communications to you via email. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time in accordance with the “What about marketing communications?” section below.

**Purpose/Activity** | **Data type** | **Lawful basis for processing**  
---|---|---  
To register you as a user | Identity data

Contact data

Profile data

| Performance of a contract with you   
To provide you with products and services you have registered to use  | Identity data

Contact data

Profile data

| Performance of a contract with you   
To administer and protect our website and provide customer services (including sending you service messages via email) | Identity data 

Contact data

Profile data

Technical data

| Performance of a contract with you 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (ensuring the proper operation of our website and our business)  
  
To verify your identity and to monitor and analyse the use of your account  | Identity data

Contact data

Profile data

Technical data

Usage data

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to prevent and detect fraudulent activity, security incidents and criminal activities) 

Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To use data to perform statistical and trend analysis | Technical data 

Usage data

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our business, website and products and to inform our marketing strategy)   
To personalise your experience on our website by delivering relevant content and advertisements  | Identity data 

Contact data

Profile data

Technical data

Usage data

Marketing and communications data

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our business, website and products and to inform our marketing strategy)  

To send you Gfinity group esports news as part of our email marketing & system message activity.

| Identity data 

Contact Data

Profile data

Technical data

Usage data

Marketing and communications data

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our business, website and products and to inform our marketing strategy) 

Consent  
  
To process your “write for us” application | Identity data 

Contact data

Profile data

| Performance of a contract with you   
  
We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please [_contact us_](https://realsport101.com/contact-us/).

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

## **How will your personal data be shared?**

We may share your personal data for the purposes/activities set out in the table above with the following:

  * any member of our group of companies (Gfinity Group, which includes [Gfinity PLC](https://www.gfinityplc.com/) and [CEVO](http://cevo.com/)), for the purpose of the business operation and administration of our group companies and for marketing purposes; and
  * selected third parties including:
  * business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with you (for example third party service providers to help us in areas such as website hosting, maintenance, digital marketing, email marketing and customer support operations);
  * with your express opt-in consent, select companies outside our group for marketing purposes;
  * advertisers and advertising networks that require the personal data to select and serve relevant adverts to you and others. We do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to our advertisers, but we will provide them with aggregate information about our users. We may also use such aggregate information to help advertisers reach the kind of audience they want to target. We may make use of the personal data we have collected from you to enable us to comply with our advertisers’ wishes by displaying their advertisement to that target audience; and
  * analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our website.

We will disclose your personal data to third parties:

  * if we are required to do so by law or pursuant to a binding regulatory request (in such circumstances, such disclosure will at all times be solely to the extent required by law or the applicable regulatory request);
  * in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we will disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets;
  * in order to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements; or
  * to protect the rights, property, or safety of our users, or others which may include exchanging information with third party companies for the purpose of fraud prevention or credit risk reduction.

## **What about marketing communications?**

Where you have given us your express consent to do so, we may from time to time contact you by email about our products and services that may be of interest to you. We may use a third party email service provider (such as MailChimp) to deliver the relevant emails to you.

We will also get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any company outside our group of companies for marketing purposes.

If at any point, you would like to opt-out of receiving such marketing communications, or would like to change the channels that are used to contact you, please click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any emails you receive, or email us, stating your preferences, at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Email marketing messages may contain tracked clickable links or similar server technologies in order to track subscriber activity within email marketing messages. Where used, such marketing messages may record a range of subscriber personal data relating to engagement, geographic, demographics and already stored subscriber personal data.

## **Downloads & media files**

Any downloadable documents, files or media made available on this website are provided to users at their own risk. While all precautions have been undertaken to ensure only genuine downloads are available users are advised to verify their authenticity using third party anti-virus software or similar applications.

We accept no responsibility for third party downloads and downloads provided by external third party websites and advise users to verify their authenticity using third party anti-virus software or similar applications.

## **S** **ecurity and storage of your personal data**

We have adopted strict security processes, in accordance with good industry practice, to prevent the unauthorised access to, or disclosure of, your personal data. We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so. In addition, we also limit access to personal data to those employees, agents, consultants and other third parties on a need-to-know basis and subject in each case to suitable obligations relating to security and confidentiality of your information.

Despite our implementation of these policies, please note that we cannot guarantee the security of any personal data that you send to us via the internet (including via email or forms on our website) or which is collected using online devices/tracking technology.

We will retain your personal data only for as long as is strictly necessary for the purposes for which such personal data was originally collected (or for such longer period as may be required by law).

## **External website links & third parties**

Although we only look to include quality, safe and relevant external links, users are advised to adopt a policy of caution before clicking any external web links mentioned throughout this website (External links are clickable text / banner / image links to other websites).

URL shortening is a technique used on the web to shorten URL’s (Uniform Resource Locators) to something substantially shorter. Users should exercise caution before clicking on shortened URL links and verify their authenticity before proceeding.

We cannot guarantee or verify the contents of any externally linked website. Users should therefore note they click on external links at their own risk and we cannot be held liable for any loss or damage caused to you by visiting any external links mentioned.

## **Comments**

Our website uses Disqus to manage comments you leave on the website. All comments you leave on the website are processed by Disqus and you should login to your Disqus profile to delete, edit and manage any comments you have left on the website. Please review the [Disqus Terms of Service](https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/terms-of-service) and [Disqus Privacy Policy](https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy) before leaving any comments on the website, as those documents will apply to your interactions with Disqus.

## **Write For Us**

In order to operate the “write for us” process we require you to add our employees on Facebook. This allows us to promptly process your application. Please review the [Facebook Privacy Policy](https://en-gb.facebook.com/full_data_use_policy) and [Facebook Terms of Service](https://www.facebook.com/terms.php) in relation to any use you may make of the Facebook platform, as those documents will apply to your activities on Facebook.

## **Social media policy & usage**

We adopt a Social Media Policy to ensure our business and our staff conduct themselves appropriately online. While we may have official profiles on social media platforms, users are advised to verify authenticity of such profiles before engaging or sharing information with such profiles. We will never ask for user passwords or personal details on social media platforms. Users are advised to conduct themselves appropriately when engaging with us on social media.

There may be instances where our website features social sharing buttons, which help share web content directly from web pages to the respective social media platforms. You use social sharing buttons at your own discretion and accept that doing so may publish content to your social media profile feed or page, and the operators of those social media platforms will have access to the personal data that you disclose.

## **Transfer of your personal data outside the EEA**

We may transfer some of your personal data to third parties who are located in countries outside of the European Economic Area (“EEA”). This may include third parties in the United States of America and other locations where group companies of ours are based. These countries may not have equivalent data protection legislation to the UK. In each case, we will not transfer your data outside of the EEA unless we have your explicit consent to do so (or have another legal justification for doing so) and where we have ensured that all adequate protections are in place in respect of the processing of such data outside of the EEA. If you require more information about these international transfer of data, please [_contact us_](https://realsport101.com/contact-us/). Where relevant, you are entitled to see a copy of any safeguards which we have put in place.

## **Your rights**

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office. We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns first so please contact us in the first instance.

## **Changes to this privacy policy**

We may update this privacy policy from time to time in our discretion and will notify you of any material changes to the way in which we treat personal data, by posting a notice on relevant areas of our website. We may also provide notice to you in other ways in our discretion, such as through contact information you have provided.

Any updated version of this privacy policy will be effective immediately upon the posting of the revised privacy policy unless otherwise specified.

Your continued use of our website after the effective date of the revised privacy policy (or such other act specified at that time) will constitute your consent to those changes. However, we will not, without your consent, use your personal data in a manner materially different than what was stated at the time your personal data was collected.

## **Contact us**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

v.0.2 May 2018: Realsm Limited

## **Resources & further information**
